mr chairman i'm pleased to speak in the
committee stages of this insurance
prudential supervision bill
uh without wishing to try your patience
mr chairman i do want to
take my few minutes in this call to
describe the bill in terms of what it is
not because sometimes describing
something in the negative is as
beneficial as describing it in the
positive
but we'll see how we go
and how much i try your patience in the
process
but mr chairman
clearly labor supports this bill
our
main concern was to ensure that it
benefited policyholders insurance policy
holders
through
ensuring the security and the
transparency
and the fairness
of a supervision scheme
and
of course we are in agreement with that
we also support
the the minister's sop
there is a 200 page bill here
mr chairman and a 10 page
supplementary order paper
and
both of those things
reflect
what the the bill could have been
but is
not we support the bill we support
the supplementary order paper
but
the question arises from the
supplementary order paper
as to whether or not
this bill
seizes the opportunity that was before
the government and before the select
committee but at the direction of the
government was in fact before the
government
in doing something essential
which this bill does and that's
encouraging
uh by its own purpose the maintenance of
a sound and efficient insurance sector
that can promote confidence amongst
policy holders and the general public
it achieves what it sets out to do
however
these are extraordinary times
to improve the insurance sector and the
transparency and security of that is a
good thing
in these
extraordinary and uncertain times
but in fact the government could have
taken the opportunity to do something
even more substantial
here is a portion
of our economic structures
being given into the hands of the
reserve bank
in order
for that monitoring and that supervisory
function to be performed
and that is a good thing
but
what the government could have done
is to have taken another look
at the functions of the reserve bank
and to have expanded its functions
in a way that addresses
a point of order
i think i can anticipate
and and uh
i think without even hearing it i'm
going to uphold it the member needs to
clarify
the argument that she's putting in
relation to the bill before us
marion street speaking to the point of
order no i've spoken and i've just said
the member must talk about the bill you
can make a comparative
example but you must draw it into the
bill
thank you mr chairman
the
treatment of the insurance sector
as i have already said
is a valid and important and justifiable
thing to do
and why not
accompany that
with some additional measures
that relate to comparable sectors in the
financial structures that we have
and deal with a comprehensive range
of financial tools
that is available to this government or
could be available to the government
with some imagination and some boldness
and yet what we have in this bill mr
chair
is a cringing timidity on the part of
this government
to that restricts it
from looking at the creation of other
financial and economic institutions or
powers within the reserve bank and
limits it only to the purpose of this
bill which is in fact
to encourage the maintenance of a sound
and efficient insurance sector
we don't disagree with that
but it cannot go unnoticed in the
context of of describing
what this bill does
that it could have done more
right the question is
that
are you seeking a call
no you're not are you
well then i will put the question
and the question is that the amendments
in the name of the honourable bill
english has set out on sop 155 be agreed
to those of that opinion will say aye
contrary no
amendments are agreed to the question
now is that parts
one to five schedules one two three and
clauses one and two as amended stand
part those of that opinion will say aye
contrary no
the motion is agreed to i will report
this bill with amendment
you